Most of us would agree that being healthy is important.
我们大多数人都会认同，健康至关重要。
We are inundated with articles in health magazines talking about the latest fad diets, or adverts that offer potential miracle cures for obesity that are often too good to be true.
健康杂志上充斥着介绍最新流行节食法的文章，各类广告也打着能神奇治愈肥胖的旗号，这些宣传往往美好得不切实际。
One of the latest crazes is fasting, often referred to as intermittent fasting.
当下最新的热潮之一是禁食，也就是我们常说的间歇性禁食。
But what is it?
但它到底是什么？
And how can it help us to lose weight?
它又如何帮我们减重？
Fasting refers to a period of abstinence from consuming food.
禁食指的是在一段时间内停止进食。
The idea of intermittent fasting is to reduce calories over a certain number of days or hours rather than a sustained period.
间歇性禁食的核心理念是，在特定的几天或几个小时内减少热量摄入，而非长期持续节食。
It has been linked to longevity and generally improved health. It also helps those interested in keeping off the weight or dropping a few pounds.
这种饮食方式与长寿和整体健康水平提升相关，也能帮到那些想要维持体重或是减掉几斤肉的人。
There are also different ways to fast.
禁食的方式也分很多种。
For example, in the 5:2 diet, you eat normally on five days of a week and reduce your calorie intake on the other two.
比如5:2轻断食法，即一周中有五天正常饮食，另外两天减少热量摄入。
Then there's a restricted-hours diet that sees people only eating during a limited part of the day, for example, over eight hours.
还有限时进食法，即人们只在一天中的固定时段内进食，比如8小时进食窗口。
But is it for everyone?
但这种方式适合所有人吗？
Well, before we get to that, let's look at some of the possible benefits.
在解答这个问题之前，我们先来看看它可能带来的一些益处。
A study published on the National Library of Medicine website suggests that intermittent fasting may help with the control of blood sugar and potentially lower the risk of diabetes.
发表在美国国家医学图书馆网站上的一项研究表明，间歇性禁食可能有助于控制血糖，还有可能降低患糖尿病的风险。
However, more research on this is needed.
不过，这一结论还需要更多研究佐证。
Other studies have claimed that some form of intermittent fasting may help to prevent some diseases, aid with metabolism, slow the ageing process, support brain function, and help to shed weight.
另有研究称，某些形式的间歇性禁食或有助于预防部分疾病、促进新陈代谢、延缓衰老、维持大脑功能，同时帮助减重。
And what about the downsides?
那它的弊端又有哪些呢？
Well, this diet is not for everyone.
首先，这种饮食方式并非适合所有人。
Fasting might not suit those who are underweight or with a long-term medical condition.
体重过轻或是患有慢性基础病的人群可能并不适合禁食。
Fasting may cause some people to experience symptoms such as headaches or make them prone to overeating after a reduced calorie intake day.
禁食可能会让部分人出现头痛等症状，或是在低热量摄入日之后出现暴饮暴食的倾向。
As with many diets, it's always wise to speak to your doctor or weight loss professional before changing your eating habits.
和大多数节食方法一样，在改变饮食习惯前，咨询医生或减重专业人士永远是明智的选择。
And, at the end of the day, it could just come down to what lifestyle choice suits you.
说到底，它取决于你更适合哪种生活方式。